IBRAHIM YUSUF HUSSEIN

P.O Box 554-00208, Ngong-Hills

Phone: +254-797-888-041

Email: ibrahim353yusuf@gmail.com.

Personal Profile

I am a creative and self-driven web developer and Electrical and Electronics Engineer with 4 years of experience in Automation Engineering in the Oil and Gas industry. Additionally, I have 1.5 years of experience as a freelance web developer, looking to utilize my skills to build and develop efficient technical solutions in software development.

Career Objectives

My focus is on being a valuable team member who contributes through learning, sharing and accomplishing set goals. Furthermore, I aim to apply my industry experience to enhance existing products and services.

Skills

- Languages: JavaScript, React JS, HTML5, CSS3, Node JS, Tailwind CSS and Next JS.
- Database: MongoDB.
- Version Control: Git and GitHub.
- Scrum: Agile way to manage projects.
- Basic Knowledge of Rest API (Postman).
- Familiarity with SEO and Google analytics .

Projects.

- **Demo Coffee Site Front-end** I designed and coded this demo weather application using React JS, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS. Accessible design practices were used to ensure the site is usable by all users. Here is the link to the project.
- **Personal Portfolio** I designed and coded this portfolio website using React JS, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and SASS. The main focus was to develop a responsive and user-friendly website with cross-browser compatibility. <u>Here</u> is the link to the site.
- Movie Review Website I designed and coded this demo movie web application using React JS, React Bootstrap, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and TheMovieDB API. The goal was to create a responsive design for a great user experience on all devices. Here is the link to the site.
- **Gym Fitness Website** I designed this project using JavaScript, HTML, and CSS and ensured a responsive design for a seamless experience on all devices. <u>Here</u> is link to the project.
- Omirieri Advocates Site I developed this website using CMS WordPress and basic CSS to customize some features. The design is accessible for all users. View the site here.

Links

More of my projects can be found on my GitHub page together with the code syntax of projects above. <u>Here</u>.

Link to my personal portfolio. Here.

Professional Experience

Nexgen Fuel Works

Automations Dept. (Oct 2021 -Present)

Responsibilities include:

- Installing and maintaining fuel automation systems (fusion, tag reader, ATG, and POS) at major petrol stations (Total Energies, Rubis Energy, and Lexo Energy).
- Installing, maintaining, and repairing computer systems and POS devices.
- Servicing dispensing units and maintaining fuel dispenser electronics.
- Staging equipment for troubleshooting and integration testing to improve reliability.
- Performing network services such as port forwarding, communication port assignment, DNS server optimization, and VPN network maintenance.

Freelance Web developer

(Sep 2021 -Present)

Responsibilities include;

- Designing and developing websites and web apps using various programming languages, content management systems (CMS) as well as creating custom CMS for static site generation.
- Redesigning and improving existing websites.
- Integrating websites with third-party services and APIs.
- Optimizing websites for speed, security, and search engine optimization (SEO).
- Providing ongoing maintenance and technical support for websites.
- Debugging and fixing technical issues on existing websites.

Shankan Enterprises

Automation and control engineer/technologist.

Automations Dept. (Jan 2019 –Oct 2021).

Responsibilities include:

- Expert in installing, maintaining, and repairing computer systems and electronics.
- Connecting A.T.S tag readers to pumping units to monitor pump attendant sales.
- Training system users on equipment operation through user guides and training sessions.
- Analyzing system log files to identify and resolve issues, sharing findings to prevent reoccurrence.
- Staging equipment for troubleshooting and integration tests, improving repeatability and reliability.

Epha Ventures Limited

Assistant IT Trainee (April 2015-Dec 2017).

Responsibilities included:

- Providing comprehensive computer networking solution to enhance organizational efficiency.
- Offering technical support and troubleshooting services for computer systems and peripherals.
- Conducting product sales and marketing.

Dot-com Computer and Laptop Repair

IT intern (Jan 2013-Sep 2014).

The roles that I conducted were:

- •Installing and repairing of computer systems together with the peripherals, UPS and server systems.
- Data recovery of lost data from corrupted computers and servers.
- Conducting computer networking services for private companies and offices.

Education

2013 – 2019: Technical University of Kenya

B. Eng. Electrical and Electronic Engineering (Automation and Control option)

Certification

- 1. Google fundamentals of digital marketing.
- 2. Bachelors of Engineering in Electrical and Electronics
- 3. Agile and Scrum Fundamentals.
- 4. AWS certified cloud practitioner (currently undertaking it under Udemy).

Interests and Hobbies

- 1. Reading on self-improvement books, Engineering and environment topics.
- 2. Physical training and exercise.

Referees

Available upon request.